# Salman Al Farisi

(+62) 812 9003 4684 salman.consulting@outlook.com Jl. Komando III No.10 RT.11/RW.2, Karet, Setiabudi, Jakarta Selatan, Jakarta

Research Assistant on the ITB Department of Astronomy with a focus in machine learning. 3 years working on practical machine-learning library development. Completed IBM AI Engineer Professional Certificate.

Previously had a certain amount of internships at startups, 4 years participation in Data Science and Information Security competitions, captaining a collegiate Information Security team, leading a team for national scale college events, and performing social public outreach.

#### Experience

#### 01/2020 - Present

Ignitus Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania

## Machine Learning Intern

Development of a MOOC on the basic concepts of Machine Learning, deploy machine learning models in production as API with Flask and creation of 10 separate modules/courses/tutorials about the 10 main Python libraries for ML.

#### 01/2020 - Present

Astronomy Department, Bandung Institute of Technology Bandung, West Java

### Research Assistant

Assisting research on astronomical big data, galaxy classification, and neural network for GAIA database and spectral classification. developing the web service for Indonesia Astronomy Olympiad National Team.

#### 08/2019 - 12/2019

Introduction to Computation Laboratory, Bandung Institute of Technology Bandung, West Java

### Infrastructure Team

Responsible as DevOps software engineer for infrastructure in course and lab, in terms of the website, moodle, pipeline, and any system related. Providing good UI and UX on students practical session, security systems, and system availability. Fixing previous bugs on SQL database schemas, PHP scripts, building a new platform with React.

#### 06/2019 - 08/2019

Chatbiz.id Bandung, West Java

## **Data Scientist Intern**

Created business insight as a web service from user transaction data to be converted into business activity analytics.

Skills	✓ Python	✓ Data Science
	✓ Business Intelligence	✓ Machine Learning
	✓ Deep Learning	✓ Robotics
	✓ SQL	✓ Google Cloud Platform
	✓ Computer Vision	✓ Docker
	✓ JavaScript	✓ R

✓ Data Analytics	✓ Spark
✓ Linux	✓ Statistics

#### **Education**

## Astronomy

07/2020 • Institut Teknologi Bandung

Bandung, West Java

Third prize in 2018 National Robotics Competition: Humanoid Division. Achieving The Rising Star Award for highest GPA increment. Final project research on Spectral Prediction of Stellar Temperature, Surface Gravity, and Metallicity using CNN. Achieving a test accuracy of 93%.

#### **Economics**

07/2016 • Universitas Indonesia

Jakarta

Competed in National Robotics Contest: Humanoid Division. Achieving a cum-laude GPA for the first semester. Transferred to ITB at 2016.

Languages English Japanese
Indonesian